<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>ShenZhen on Eric Blog</title>
        <link>https://ericrzhu.com/en/tags/shenzhen/</link>
        <description>Recent content in ShenZhen on Eric Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 14:35:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ericrzhu.com/en/tags/shenzhen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Tencent Internship Experience</title>
        <link>https://ericrzhu.com/en/p/tencent-internship-experience/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 14:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ericrzhu.com/en/p/tencent-internship-experience/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://ericrzhu.com/en/p/tencent-internship-experience/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Tencent Internship Experience" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;英文的码一下，有空再补&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;点击标题下面的&lt;code&gt;中文按钮&lt;/code&gt;，切换成中文&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two months of internship at Tencent, I have now returned to school. Let’s record this first internship experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for-an-internship&#34;&gt;Looking for an internship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in the second semester of my junior year, I wanted to enrich my life during the summer vacation, so I started looking for an internship (&lt;del&gt;Because if you don&amp;rsquo;t find it yourself, you can only accept the internship arranged by the school, which is very boring.&lt;/del&gt;). There are three gold medals and four silvers when looking for summer internships. Generally, the summer internships of large factories start to be approved in advance for interviews in March. But my delivery time was relatively late, it was only in April, so I only caught up with the official approval. At the beginning, with the mentality of not being afraid of tigers, I invested in big Internet companies. I thought that as long as one could ask me, I did not make any preparations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember that the first interview was with Meituan. Because there was no preparation at all, the whole process was a little embarrassing. Basically, 60% of the questions could not be answered, and then I received a rejection letter two days later (&lt;del&gt;has placed you in the talent pool&lt;/del&gt;), and the same is true for the interview of NetEase Interactive Entertainment. After thinking about the pain, I began to read the face-to-face scriptures to make some preparations, brush the algorithm questions, review the knowledge of Jiwang, and so on &lt;code&gt;我感觉计网，数据库的东西是面试的时候最喜欢问的，不过等大四做毕设后也知道为什么了，后端程序员基本上每天接触的就是这俩东西&lt;/code&gt;. The effect is quite remarkable. After several interviews, I can basically pass one side, but I still die on two sides (&lt;del&gt;For example, NetEase Cloud Music, I thought it was relatively stable when it reached the third side.&lt;/del&gt;). Seeing that the time is getting tighter and thinking that the development paper will not be included, let’s change direction and apply for the test development position of Tencent. After three long interviews, I was lucky enough to pass. I remember that when HR called me, I was very I was so excited that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even understand which department I was recorded by, only a certain department of CSIG.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
